foreign
[Music]
I've done videos on drugs for hair
growth supplements for hair growth and
foods for hair growth what about natural
options that you can apply topically I
ended my food video on this study
suggesting consuming pumpkin seed oil
could increase hair growth what about
just rubbing it on your scalp it works
in mice but what about men or in this
case women pumpkin seed oil about a
quarter teaspoon rubbed onto the scalp
once a day was tested head to head
against minoxidil foam five percent once
a day for three months in women with
age-related pattern hair loss both
treatments worked but the drug worked
better though at about five times the
cost
similar experiment comparing a topical
of 0.2 percent caffeine solution which
is about five times stronger than coffee
with five percent minoxidil found they
work similarly well for balding men
though like in the pumpkin seed oil
trial there was no third placebo group
to ensure that they all weren't just
somehow getting better on their own for
example due to seasonal influence with
typically greater hair shedding in the
fall than the spring
dripping caffeine on human hair
follicles growing in a Petri dish
enhances hair growth and indeed when
finally put to the test against Placebo
one out for both female and male pattern
baldness with 85 percent satisfied after
unknowingly using the caffeine
containing shampoo for six months
compared to only 36 in the placebo
shampoo group
egcg one of the major constituents of
green tea also can promote human hair
growth in vitro and may help balding
mice but I failed to find any green tea
clinical trials
protheon zinc shampoo typically used for
dandruff beta Placebo for increasing
hair density and balding men after 26
weeks but not enough for the study
subjects to notice any difference
working less than half as well as the
five percent minoxidil
what about topical herbal treatments
used since time immemorial Ginger offers
a good cautionary Tale
ginger has a long history of traditional
use in Asia to Halt hair loss and
heighten hair growth do a quick search
for ginger shampoo and turnip one
thousand entries but when the National
Science Foundation of China finally put
it to the test researchers were
surprised that actually suppressed human
hair growth given their results they
suggested Ginger could instead be used
for the removal of unwanted body hair
Chinese nut weed known in traditional
Chinese medicine circles as husho Wu is
a flowering plant in the buckwheat
family popularized as a hair tonic like
green tea there are promising in vitro
and rodent studies but no human clinical
trials Rosemary however has been put to
the test
100 balding men were randomized to twice
a day of minoxidil versus a rosemary
lotion it took six months but eventually
there was significant comparable
improvements in hair counts in both
groups the Rosemary lotion appeared to
work as well as the drug you can make it
at home by mixing 10 drops of Rosemary
essential oil per fluid ounce to your
favorite lotion and then rubbing a
quarter teaspoon onto your scalp twice a
day and that much rosemary oil would
cost about a penny a week
oh
foreign